I would like to ask a question
regarding my personality.
I am a perfectionist in all things.
I try to micromanage even
the smallest things.
And that has created
so much stress for me.
I worry constantly about work, and
when my subordinates do something wrong,
I get very upset all of a sudden.
I keep telling myself to be patient,
but that hasn't helped.
I'd appreciate your advice on this.
I would call this ingrained.
You have some psychological anxiety
from an event from childhood.
Because you have this
anxiety towards yourself,
you can experience large mood swings.
If your anxiety becomes serious,
you need to be treated by a psychiatrist.
Even if it's not at that level, you should
always be aware that you have this anxiety.
I am not trying to say anything
bad about your mother,
but she also had this anxiety.
This anxiety influenced your
emotional development,
and you have this anxiety
ingrained in you.
You need to be aware of this.
“My anxiety does not come from
someone else’s behavior.”
“I simply have this anxiety, which gets
amplified in certain situations.”
So you need to let go of
the attitude of blaming others.
Anxiety is a problem
that is hard to improve.
When you feel anxious,
don't blame others for those feelings.
If you feel upset or irritated,
don't blame someone for that.
If you are aware that your internal state
is causing your anxiety to increase,
this awareness will help you
to overcome the situation.
So don't look outside but inward.
Pray like this.
While doing 108 prostrations…
Are you Christian? Buddhist? No religion?
(Questioner) I'm Christian.
Then pray, "Dear Lord, I am at peace."
If you keep thinking about how anxious
you are, you'll become more anxious.
So pray that you are at peace.
"Through Lord's grace, I can manage."
"Thank you for your grace."
If you want to improve more quickly,
psychologically, you'll be more anxious.
So appreciate that it
hasn't been too serious.
And think this is all to Lord's grace.
Do you understand?
You need to bring on
the feeling of gratitude.
If it is too serious,
you need to get treated.
But, since it is not, I am
grateful to live as I do.
Second, you need to keep on implanting
that you are at peace.
Stop dwelling on the thought
that you have a problem.
If you keep on implanting
that you are at peace,
the anxiety in your subconscious
will subside little bit at a time.
Don't think about it too seriously.
First, keep on implanting
that you are at peace.
Next, thank Lord's grace
that your anxiety is not too severe.
Generate the feelings of thankfulness.
If you do that, your anxiety
will get better gradually.
(Questioner) Thank you.